<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on PONG - Texas A&amp;M</title>
    <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on PONG - Texas A&amp;M</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 PONG</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pong-tamu.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing by wave trapping</title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/research/niw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/research/niw/</guid>
      <description>The Texas-Louisiana shelf in the northern Gulf of Mexico is an ideal, geophysical lab to study near-inertial waves (NIWs) within submesoscale vortices. It is a broad, shallow shelf characterized by large inputs of fresh water from the Mississippi River. Submesoscale vortices within the river plume front are prevalent over the shelf in summertime, coexisting with strong NIWs generated by the land-sea breeze.
The figure below shows the ray tracing within an anti-cyclone over the shelf based on a realistic numerical simulation; it suggests that the enhanced mixing in the stratified interior is highly related to the downward radiation of NIWs and the consequent wave trapping within the anti-cyclone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submesoscale baroclinic instabilities</title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/research/ngbib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/research/ngbib/</guid>
      <description>Baroclinic instabilities are ubiquitous in open oceans but seldom observed in coastal zones, even though lateral density gradients within coastal fronts are often stronger than those of open ocean fronts. This study attempts to demonstrate the self-inhibiting effect of the submesoscale baroclinic instabilities in buoyancy-driven flow. We explored the non-geostrophic baroclinic instability theories adapted to the scenario with sloping bathymetry and demonstrates the suppression of instabilities, through a reduction in growth rate, in the non-geostrophic limit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>